Guide to the Edmund Burke Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Edmund Burke letters]
1778-1825
OSBORN C8
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.1
(1 volume)
Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn c8. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
- BURKE, EDMUND, 1729-1797
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester, (1755-1827) (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Beaconsfield
    2 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
    An invitation to come over from
    Ireland.
    8/1
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [ca. 1792 Sep 7] (Box 1)
    n.p.
    Journey to Bath.
    8/2
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1794 Aug 28 (Box 1)
    3 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
    8/3
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1784 Nov 19 (Box 1)
    2 p.; 20 x 18 cm.
    The health of King's brother
    sojourning in Nice.
    8/4
  - ALS to Frances Anne (Greville) Crewe, lady Crewe (d. 1818), 1796 Mar 17 (Box 1)
    2 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
    The health of personal acquaintances.
    8/5
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1797 Mar 21 (Box 1)
    Bath
    3 p.; 24 x 19 cm. Personal financial matters. 8/6
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1796 Mar 23 (Box 1)
    Personal financial matters.
    8/7
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1796 Jun 4 (Box 1)
    Personal financial matters; Burke
    needs money.
    8/8
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1796 Nov 4 (Box 1)
    3 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
    The financial matters of a mutual
    friend.
    8/9
  - ALS to [Edward James] Nagle, [1796] Nov 7 (Box 1)
    2 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
    Publishing matters.
    8/10
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1794] Nov 30 (Box 1)
    8/11
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1797 Jan 25 (Box 1)
    3 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
    The religious education of a child
    Richard Brockelsby (1722-1797).
    8/12
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1796] (Box 1)
    [1796 after May 14]
    1 p.; 18 x 12 cm. Financial matters. "Burke Correspondence", ix. 8/14
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1796 Apr] (Box 1)
    4 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
    "Burke Correspondence", viii, 460.
    8/15
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1795] (Box 1)
    [1795 after Nov 30]
    1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
    The king's wife and niece; thoughts
    on regicide and current Parliamentary
    discussions.
    "Burke Correspondence", viii, 353.
    8/16
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester 1755-1827), [1796 Mar] (Box 1)
    1 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
    Mrs. Craven's dispute with a bishop.
    "Burke Correspondence", viii, 453.
    8/17
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1796 Oct 24 (Box 1)
    1 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
    The loss of a new addition to an
    edition to be reprinted.
    8/18
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1796] Nov 23 (Box 1)
    3 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
    Discusses proposed publications.
    8/19
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1796] Dec 21 (Box 1)
    Discusses religious education.
    8/20
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1796] Dec 30 (Box 1)
    About a 3rd letter on the prospect
    of a Peace.
    8/21
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1797 May 16 (Box 1)
    "Madness" in England and Ireland
    Dr. Troy, catholic archbishop of
    Dublin.
    8/22
  - AL to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1792 Sep 20 (Box 1)
    The business of the committee on the
    French immigrants; letter is not
    entirely in the hand of Burke.
    8/23
  - Autograph Envelope to Walker King, bp. Rochester (1755-1827), 1792 Oct 25 (Box 1)
    8 x 12 cm
    Postal Cancellations.
    8/24
  - AL to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1792 Sep 18] (Box 1)
    Further discussion about the French
    immigrants.
    "Burke Correspondence", vii, 214.
    8/25
  - AL to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1796] (Box 1)
    [1796 after Mar 24]
    The grant to Penn School.
    "Burke Correspondence", viii, 445.
    8/26
  - AL to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1796] (Box 1)
    [1796 after Oct 24]
    Discusses an "insertion" presumably
    for a publication; mentions various
    French nobles; partly written by
    Miss Hickey.
    "Burke Correspondence", ix.
    8/27
- BURKE, JANE MARY (NUGENT), 1734-1812
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1797 or later] (Box 1)
    1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
    Financial matters.
    8/28
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), undated (Box 1)
    1 p.; 24 x 18 cm.
    Personal and financial matters.
    8/29
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1799 Jul 15 (Box 1)
    Business concerning Mr. Noble and
    Mr. Smith; mentions William Henry
    Cavendish Bentinck, 3rd duke of
    Portland (1738-1809).
    8/30
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1800 Jan 31 (Box 1)
    On the death of the bishop of Bangor.
    8/31
- BOURKE, JOHN
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1778 Mar 10 (Box 1)
    3 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
    Thoughts on England's reputation
    abroad.
    8/32
- BURKE, RICHARD, 1758-1794
  - ALS to [Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827)], undated (Box 1)
    On William Henry Cavendish Bentinck,
    3rd duke of Portland (1738-1809).
    8/33
  - ALS to John King, [1792] Feb 9 (Box 1)
    8/34
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1794 Jun 21] (Box 1)
    2 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
    8/35
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), [1793 Jul] (Box 1)
    8/36
- FITZWILLIAM, WILLIAM WENTWORTH, 2ND EARL, 1748-1833
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1794 Aug (Box 1)
    Wentworth
    On the death of Richard Burke, Jr.
    (1758-1794).
    8/37
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1794 Aug 7 (Box 1)
    York
    2 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
    8/38
  - ALS to Walker King, bp. of Rochester (1755-1827), 1825 Nov 10 (Box 1)
    1 p.; 16 x 12 cm.
    On Charles X of France (1757-1836)
    as a Burke reader.
    8/39
- STOCKDALE, JOHN
  - ALS to Richard Brocklesby (1722-1797), 1796 Apr 8 (Box 1)
    Piccadilly [London]
    Seeks manuscript of Regicide Peace.
    8/40
- KING, WALKER, BP. OF ROCHESTER, 1755-1827
  - AL(draft) to Charles X, king of France (1757-1836), [1825] (Box 1)
    Sends copy of Burke's "Works".
    8/41